Fedor Lisin

Data Scientist

Moscow, Russia RU

↑ TheoLisin ② @TedFox in theo-lisin

It took me around two years to realise that I like programming in general and data science in particular. Since taking the Yandex classes, well-written, readable code has become my intention. My current focus is creating products that benefit or facilitate the lives of people, not just reviewers.

SKILLS

ML and Data Science Intermediate Sklearn PyTorch statistics FastAPI Pydantic ORM Docker Docker Compose SQLAlchemy ML frameworks Github Actions Gitlab Pipelines

Common

VSC	Gitlab		Github		
Reviewing		L	ir	านx	

WORK EXPERIENCE (3)

Python Developer at Huawei 2024 - Current

Research on ways to improve the quality of service (QoS) in Wi-Fi systems.

Python Developer at Supervisely OÜ

2023 - 2023

- Create a new app on the Supervisely platform and provide client tech help.
- Developed new SOTA model training and serving applications for the Supervisely ecosystem (PIPs, YOLO, MMDetection, MixFormer etc.).
- Enhanced capabilities of the SDK: support for point and object tracking with NN models and linear interpolation
- Provided platform users with technical support

Junior Data Scientist at OCRV, Russian Railways affiliated company

2021 - 2022

Developed different models from scratch for tabular data and time series, upgraded the current data infrastructure, supervised the students' self-study pet projects.

- Train delay investigation system: improving data infrastructure, time to create the final dataset was at least cut in half. (Catboost, SQL, ClickHouse)
- EEG motor imaginary classification: examining the primary methods for getting, classifying, and filtering EEG data, as well as developing experimental data collection methods. (ICA, SSP, WPD)
- Recommendation system for ticket sales (students project): aided students in using their repository and fixed django framework issues. (Git, Conda, Django)

PROJECTS (2)

Voice emotion recognition using Wav2Vec

2021 - 2021

 ${\color{red} \underline{C}}'' https://github.com/TheoLisin/Emotion_Recognition_with_Wav2Vec$

Wav2Vec transformers telegram-api

Speech emotion recognition model based on Wav2Vec with telegam-bot user interface.

- Trained 8-class classifier on RAVDESS dataset using Wav2Vec pre-trained model.
- Developed a Telegram bot to gather more data and test the model on Russian speech.

Monotone Hurwitz numbers in genus zero

2019 - 2020

mathematical physics graph theory

a la a la ala dia a d

University-authored bachelor's thesis

EDUCATION (2)

Bachelor Theoretical Physics at St. Petersburg Academic University of RAS

2016 - 2020

Data Science, MLOps at MADE Data Academy

2022 - 2023

CERTIFICATES

Machine learning | course authored by Stanford University

Coursera, Stanford University

2020-07-25

Machine Learning Engineer

MADE Data Academy

2023-07

 $\begin{tabular}{ll} \square https://data.vk.company/curriculum/certificates/download/12961/f84e3606-6030-4ce7-895f-4b2defe55aff/leadings/figures/download/12961/f84e3606-6030-4ce7-895f-4b2defe55aff/leadings/figures/download/12961/f84e3606-6030-4ce7-895f-4b2defe55aff/leadings/figures/download/12961/f84e3606-6030-4ce7-895f-4b2defe55aff/leadings/figures/download/12961/f84e3606-6030-4ce7-895f-4b2defe55aff/leadings/figures/download/12961/f84e3606-6030-4ce7-895f-4b2defe55aff/leadings/figures/download/12961/f84e3606-6030-4ce7-895f-4b2defe55aff/leadings/figures/download/12961/f84e3606-6030-4ce7-895f-4b2defe55aff/leadings/figures/download/12961/f84e3606-6030-4ce7-895f-4b2defe55aff/leadings/figures/download/12961/f84e3606-6030-4ce7-895f-4b2defe55aff/leadings/figures/download/12961/f84e3606-6030-4ce7-895f-4b2defe55aff/leadings/figures/download/12961/f84e3606-6030-4ce7-895f-4b2defe55aff/leadings/figures/download/12961/f84e3606-6030-4ce7-895f-4b2defe55aff/leadings/figures/download/12961/f84e3606-6030-4ce7-805f-4b2defe55aff/leadings/figures/download/12961/f84e3606-6030-4ce7-805f-4b2defe55aff/leadings/figures/download/12961/f84e3606-6030-4ce7-805f-4b2defe55aff/leadings/figures/download/12961/f84e3606-6030-4ce7-805f-4b2defe55aff/leadings/figures/download/12961/f84e3606-6030-4ce7-805f-4b2defe55aff/leadings/figures/download/12961/f84e3606-6030-4ce7-805f-4b2defe55aff/leadings/figures/download/12961/f84e3606-6030-4ce7-805f-4b2defe55aff/leadings/figures/download/12961/f84e3606-6030-4ce7-805f-4b2defe55aff/leadings/figures/download/12961/f84e3606-6030-4ce7-805f-4b2defe55aff/leadings/figures/download/fi$

LANGUAGES

English Intermediate Russian
Native Speaker

INTERESTS
Games

Airplanes

Traveling